

Ueslei Santos Lima

Software Developer

uesleisantoslima@gmail.com

+55 79 996442111

Aracaju

www.uesleilima.com

.

linkedin.com/in/uesleilima in

Analyst and developer of information technology systems, with leadership skills and experience in web, mobile, embedded and service oriented systems, as also in financial and robust batch processing systems. Fast learner and easily adaptable. Enthusiast of agile software development process.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

Java, C#, Python

Development Frameworks Spring, .NET, Django

Software Engineering Microservices, Integration Patterns,

Scrum, Agile, DevOps

Databases (

Oracle, SQL Server

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer

Backbase

02/2018 – Present Amsterdam

- Achievements/Tasks

- Development of product integration into core baking systems of large financial institutions across EU;

- Product customization for enabling Open Banking and SEPA payments regulations for biggest financial institution in Ireland.

Software Developer

Banese Bank

02/2015 – Present Aracaju, Brazil

Bank of Sergipe State

Tasks/Achievements

- System analyst and backend (JEE) developer of the bank core financial transaction authorization system;
- Brought Integration testing automatization (IBM Rational Integration Tester expert) and process-structured code-review to the team;
- Team substitute Scrum Master & Tech Leader / Member of the company Software Architecture Committee;
- RESTful API 's designer and developer in both Java Spring and C# .NET platforms, also Spring Batch / Integration developer;

Software Engineer

HP Inc

02/2014 – 02/2015 Sao Paulo, Brazil

Hewlett-Packard's Brazil R&D Branch

- Tasks/Achievements
- Software Engineer of FutureSmart Multi-function Printer Firmware;
- Frontend/backend development of the Web application interface (C# / JavaScript)
- Web services maintenance and development;
- Active participant of R&D discussion groups and development of ideas;

Software Developer

Mikromatica Group

06/2014 – Present Sorocaba, Brazil

- Tasks/Achievements
- Development of ASP.NET / WebForms / C# / Entity Framework application for Metrology management;
- DevOps engineer Microsoft Azure hosting and monitoring / SQL Azure;

WORK EXPERIENCE

System Engineer

CESAR - Recife Advanced Systems and Research Center

02/2013 - 02/2014

Tasks/Achievements

- Software and systems engineering, Java (JSE/Swing) development, distributed systems architecture design;
- Windows Mobile application entire life-cycle development (Conception, brainstorming, benchmarking and coding in XAML/C#)

Software Development Analyst

Intellisys Informatica Ltda

02/2012 – 02/2013

Tasks/Achievements

- CRM system Web application frontend/backend development and database maintenance;
- Mobile application conception, analysis and development (Android)

SOFT SKILLS

Leadership Resiliency Perspicacity

EDUCATION

Bachelor in Computer Science University of Santa Cruz - UESC

03/2007 - 07/2012

(Fully Government Paid)

Postgraduate in Software ArchitecturePontifical Catholic University of Minas Gerais PUC Minas

03/2017 - Present

CERTIFICATES

Summit - Digital Payments And Distributed Technologies (03/2017 – 03/2017)

The challenges of using Blockchain in traditional banking system

Microsoft Certified Solutions Developer - Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 (01/2013 – Present)

Scrum and XP: Best practices for project management success. (03/2011 – 03/2011)

Secure Software Development (11/2016 – 11/2016)

Agile for IT Professionals (08/2012 – 08/2012)

WEB Development with ASP.NET e C# (05/2010 – 05/2010)

INTERESTS

 IoT
 AI
 Cloud Computing
 Software Architecture
 SOA
 Omni-Channel
 REST API
 Distributed Systems

 Blockchain
 Containerization

ORGANIZATIONS

Computer Science Academic Center (04/2011 – 04/2012)

President

Sorocaba, Brazil

Itabuna, Brazil